翻译校对       Mam
日  听      HARERE
日听校对       Syura
翻译        银苹果
时间轴       乐小皓
压制       娜夏
OP&ED       葉隠
Syura
诸神字幕组
"Luxury Confectionaries"
あ ありえん
"Fujioka"
It's not possible...
Ah, come on in, everyone.
いらっしゃい 皆さん
It's not much, but please,
make yourself at home.
なんにもないところですが　どうぞごゆっくり
I'll put some tea on, right now.
今お茶入れますね
Oh, but I'm sorry,
I don't have enough cups.
でも　すいません　カップが足りなくて
どうぞ
Be my guest.
Sir, what kind of house is this?
殿
何これ　この家
Is this some sort of set? Of all the...
何かのセット
いくらなんでも
落ち着け
J-j-just calm down! I'm sure
this is just the storeroom.
きっとここは　物置なのだ
The unlimited cosmos is
probably just beyond that closet.
たぶんあの押入れの向こうには
無限大に広がるコスモが
Well, should we open the closet?
じゃ　押入れ開けてみる
- No, don't!
- 'kay!
やめとけ
そうそう　せっかくお昼ごろにくるんだから
Oh, yes, you've come
over right at lunchtime,
so my dad said to offer you something.
父が何かお出ししろって
To make sure it would suit your tastes,
皆さんのお口に合うように
I've been fasting for the last three days,
and saving up that money.
三日前から断食して食費を貯めて
I also had to spend my nest egg.
ついでにへそくり叩いちゃいました
じゃん　豪華特上寿司
Ta-da! Special-deluxe sushi!
How about that?
"Supermarket-pack sushi"
どうだ　なんちゃって
Haru-chan, we're sorry
we came to visit you!
ハルちゃん　僕ら遊びに来てごめんね
"Sob Sob"
Don't cry! Don't let these last
three days for Haruhi be for nothing,
泣くな
ハルヒの三日間を粗末にせず　心していただけ
- just eat with care!
- But these pickings are so slim!
ネタが薄いよ
もしかしてこれ　大トロじゃないですか
"Whoa!"
Wow! By any chance,
is this fancy tuna?
食べるの初めてだ
This is my first time eating any.
"Ahhh..."
"Chomp!"
"Munch-munch!"
Fancy tuna is delicious!
大トロおいしい
"Delicious!"
"Munch-munch!"
T-that's just ordinary lean tuna,
それはただの赤身であって
and is by no means fancy tuna!
断じて大トロではありません
夢…か
It was a dream?
おはようございます　環坊っちゃま
Good morning, Master Tamaki.
"Suou 2nd Residence Chief of Staff,
Maezono Shima (82)"
すぐに出かける　至急車を回してください
I'm leaving at once. Please
bring the car around immediately.
Yes, Master.
はい　坊っちゃま
恐れながら環様　ご朝食はいかがなさいます
Begging your pardon, Tamaki-sama,
but what will you have for breakfast?
"Screech"
Ah, enough! There's no time for that!
ああ　もう　今はそれどころではないのだ
My head is filled with a
dreadful foreboding right now.
俺の頭は今恐ろしい予感でいっぱいなのだ
Out of regard for their privacy,
プライバシーを考慮し
I have not sought to intrude
into club members' private lives.
部員の私生活には踏み込むまいと思ってきたが
しかし
However, if Haruhi really is
living a life as poor as that,
皆さんのお口に合うように
もしもハルヒがあのような貧困生活を送っていたとしたら
三日前から断食して食費を貯めて
then I have to see Haruhi right away,
一刻も早くハルヒに会い　真相を究明せねば
and find out the truth of the matter.
I have to get to school!
早く学校に
Begging your pardon, Tamaki-sama!
おそれながら環様
お召し物が半分お寝巻き
You are still half-dressed in pajamas,
and you still have house
slippers on your feet.
お足元は部屋履きのままにございます
My, what poor manners.
お行儀の悪い
All right, once again, I will be off.
では　改めて行ってきます
誠に恐れながら　環様
Sincerely begging your
pardon, Tamaki-sama,
but today is Sunday,
so there is no school today.
本日は日曜ゆえ　学校はお休みにございます
Shima, couldn't you have told
me that at the very start?
シマ　それを一番最初に言ってくれんだろうか
Your maidservant only
wishes daily for the Master
ご自分で間違いに気づかれる
立派な殿方に成長されますよう
to grow up to be a fine gentleman,
capable of realizing his own mistakes.
婆やは日々願っておりますゆえ
ご予定がないのなら　このシマと作法の勉強いたしましょう
If you have no other plans,
come and study your manners with me.
I have other plans! I have other plans!
ご予定ならあるぞ
Somebody, bring me the phone!
誰か　電話をここへ
Here.
Tch...
Kyoya, is that you? I need to discuss
something important with you.
鏡夜か　折り入って相談がある
''A Day in the Life of the Fujioka Family!''
I got the advertised specials!
"Marutomi Supermarket"
広告の品ゲット
The supermarket really is the place
to spend a Sunday morning.
やっぱり日曜はスーパーの朝市だな
Once I get home, I've got
cleaning and laundry to do...
帰ったら掃除と洗濯して
あれ　何だろう　うちのアパートの前に
Huh?
What's this, out front of our apartment?
何だ何だ　どこの金持ちだ
- What is this? Who're the rich people?
- Master, if you please...
お坊っちゃま　どうぞ
ここがハルヒんちか
Wow, so this is Haruhi's house, huh?
It's pretty big, isn't it?
Bigger than I thought.
結構でかいじゃん　意外
It has lots of rooms.
お部屋いっぱい
No, this is what's called
aggregate commoner dwelling.
いや　これは庶民の集合住宅というものだよ
Haruhi's place is probably just
one of the rooms among these.
恐らくハルヒのうちはこの中のどれか一室だけだ
Kyoya!
鏡夜　なんなんだこの大人数は
What's with all of these people!?
Especially those two doppelgangers!
特にあのドッペルゲンガーズ
Oh. I was sure that you didn't
have the courage to come alone,
そうか　俺はてっきりお前が一人で来る勇気がないから
so it would be better
if we came en masse.
多人数のほうがいいのかと
余計なマネをしたな　では帰ろうか子供たち
I guess that was uncalled for.
Okay, children, let's go home.
No way! I don't want to go home!
いやだいやだ帰りたくないもん
I'm sorry. Forgive me.
I don't want to be alone.
すいません　ごめんなさい　一人にしちゃいや
なんだなんだ　映画の撮影か
What is this?
Some kind of movie shoot?
Rich people! Rich people!
お金持ちだ　お金持ちだ
Listen up, men. Do not forget...
いいかものども　忘れるな
これはあくまで偶々通りかかったからというさりげない訪問であり
This is just a "we happened to be
passing by" sort of nonchalant visit,
断じて藤岡家の生活水準リサーチではない
and is definitely not research on
the Fujioka family's standard of living!
しょぼい　狭い　ぼろいなどの単語は一切禁止
The words "shabby," "cramped,"
and "run-down" are absolutely forbidden!
Yes, sir!
イエッサー
間違ってもハルヒやお父上に
Under no circumstances are you
to say or do anything to make
帰ってほしいなどと思わせるような言動は
Haruhi or her father wish
that we would leave.
Too late for that. Go away, right now!
っていうか今すぐ帰れ
Haruhi!
ハルヒ
素朴さがまた良し
Plain and simple, looking good!
"The one-piece is cute"
Shut up! Get the hell out of here!
黙れ　消え失せろ
"Shriek!"
Haruhi is using incredibly dirty language!Haruhi is using incredibly dirty language!
ハルヒがものすごく汚い言葉を
- This is all your fault!
- It wasn't me.
お前らとか　お前らのせいだ
知らない
Excuse me, Haruhi-chan,
is everything all right?
ハルヒちゃん　大丈夫かい
Oh, Miss Landlady.
大家さん
あんな外車に乗って
Driving up in foreign cars like this,
この連中まさかヤクザとかかい
are these people
the Yakuza or something?
- No, um...
- Should I call the police?
いいえ
警察に通報しようか
初めまして　マダム
Pleased to meet you, madam.
ハルヒさんの友人で　須王と申します
My name is Suou, and I'm
one of Haruhi- san's friends.
あら　まあまあまあ　どうしましょう
Oh, my, my, my, what am I to do?
Miss Landlady...
大家さん
いきなり訪問して　お騒がせしてしまい　申し訳ありません
I'm terribly sorry for suddenly stopping
by like this and causing a stir.
Oh, not at all.
いいえ　そんな
ハルヒちゃん　後でお菓子を持ってったあげようね
Haruhi-chan, I'll come drop
off some snacks later, okay?
Please, make yourselves at home.
どうぞ　ごゆっくり
"Fujioka"
I'm warning you right now, you just
get a little look, like three seconds.
言っときますけど
ちょっと見るだけですよ　3秒ぐらい
Once you've seen it, you'll immediately-
見たらさっさと
Haru-chan, I brought a gift. It's cake.
"Luxury Confectionaries"
ハルちゃん　これおみやげ　ケーキだよ
いちごのと　チョコのとね　後なんかいろいろ
It has both strawberry and chocolate,
まあ　お茶ぐらいなら
- and some others, too.
- Well, I guess we can have tea.
Whew, I guess it's a little
better than my dream.
夢より幾分ましか
ショボッ
Shabby.
A wood-built, two-story 2K.
木造　二階建て　2K
That's about right for a two-person,
father-daughter commoner family.
庶民親子二人住まいならこんなもんだろう
そうね　ハルヒサイズならこの低い天井にもぶつからないだろうし
Yeah. At Haruhi's size, she won't go
hitting her head on the low ceilings.
すごくかわいらしいお部屋だよね
It's an absolutely darling little room!
いいですよ　そんな無理して褒めなくても
That's okay, you don't have to
force yourself to compliment it.
Huh? Haru-chan, we take off our shoes?
あれ　ハルちゃん　お靴は脱ぐの
はい　是非
Yes, please.
We have to take our
shoes off before going in.
ここ　靴脱いで入るんだって
なんか道場みたいなお部屋だね
This room is like a dojo, huh?
Yeah.
じゃあ　部屋履き貸してよ
Well, let us borrow some slippers.
Oh, I can see a tatami- floored
room right there.
あっ　すぐそこに座敷が見える
In that case, we don't need slippers, huh?
なら部屋履きいらないね
Okay, forgive the intrusion!
じゃ　お邪魔します
Pardon the intrusion.
お邪魔する
Excuse us.
失礼するよ
Forgive the intrusion.
お邪魔します
- Woah! Is this all?
- Ow.
もう終わりか
You wouldn't expect a light
to be hanging down there, huh?
思わぬところに照明が下がっているね
どうやら我々は庶民の住居を甘く見すぎていたようだな
It looks like we haven't given
commoners' housing enough credit.
よし　狭いから全員体育座りを心がけよう
All right, it's tight in here,
so everyone try your
best to sit gym-style.
庶民の編み出したスペース削減法だ
This is the way that commoners
came up with to cut down on space.
Just get through this. You can't
expect anything from these people.
耐えよう　この人たちに何一つ期待しちゃダメだ
I'll put some tea on.
お茶入れますね
ハルヒ　お茶なら　ほら
Oh, Haruhi,
as far as tea goes, I have
this black tea that our father
うちの父親が買ってきたアフリカみやげの紅茶　ほい
bought as a souvenir from Africa. Here.
Oh, thanks.
ありがとう
ミルクティーが合うんだけど　ミルクある
It's best as a milk tea.
Do you have any milk?
Mm-hmm, we do have some milk...
牛乳ならあるけど
バカ　なんってことをしてくれたんだお前らは
You idiots! How could you do
something like this to her?
What?
何
Are you trying to embarrass
Haruhi by giving her that stuff?
あんなものをあげて　ハルヒに恥をかかせる気か
Look! Look at how Haruhi is at
a total loss over what to do!
見ろ　ハルヒの困り果てたあの姿を
ティポットがないんだ
She doesn't have a teapot!
そしてそれを言い出せずにいるんだ
And she can't bring herself to tell us so!
H-Haruhi, I'm sorry, you
don't have to make that tea.
ハルヒ　悪い
その紅茶は入れなくてもいい
Water will be fine for us.
水でいいんだ　僕たち
Huh? Really? But I've already made it.
え　そうなの
でも　もう入れちゃったよ
"In a kyusu teapot..."
Oh, well in that case, okay.
あ　そんならいいや
"Heart-throbbing"
Whew, that was a close one.
危なかった
We were narrowly rescued
by commoners' wisdom.
かろうじて庶民の知恵に救われたな
How do you mean?
と言いますと
In this place, none of our
common knowledge holds true.
ここでは我々の常識は一切通用しない
There's no telling but one of our
offhanded remarks might inflict
"Unknown space
'It's a Commoner's World"'
何気ない一言が
ハルヒの心に多大なダメージを与えんとも限らない
serious damage upon Haruhi's
heart. Thus, in this fight...
つまりこの勝負
...whoever embarrasses
Haruhi is the loser.
ハルヒに恥をかかせた方が負けだ
"Ready for action"
I haven't the slightest idea why you
need to turn this into a contest.
なぜ勝負事に発展させる必要があるのか　皆目見当がつかん
お茶　入りましたよ
The tea is ready.
Sorry the cups don't all match.
すいません　カップ揃ってなくて
Good, at least there aren't any
chipped bowls and measuring cups.
よし　とりあえず欠けた茶碗と計量カップはないな
ハルちゃんからケーキ選んでいいよ
Haru-chan, you get to
choose your cake first.
え　いいんですか
Oh, are you sure?
いいよ　どうせ僕らはそんなの食べ慣れて
Sure.
- After all, we're used to eating this stuff.
- Well then, let's see...
えっと　それじゃ
Shh!
Are you trying to get her down?
気を利かせたつもりが
The strawberry one.
いちごの
かわいい
How cute!
- So cute, but I can't move!
- Okay, Haru-chan, you, Takashi,
"Impatient"
かわいいが動けん
じゃあ　ハルちゃんと僕がイチゴで　あとは　もういいや…
なにかハルヒを傷つけてしまうかわからん
- There's no telling what
might offend Haruhi!
- and me will have strawberry,
恐れるべし庶民ワールドのワナ
- The traps of the commoner's
world are terrifying!
- and the others can have what they want.
"Give"
You like strawberries?
好きなのか　いちご
Yes! Thank you.
はい　ありがとうございます
行動してよかったのか
Should we have taken action!?
I wanted to give them to her!
俺あげたかったのに
We were taken in!
図られた
Ah, after eating that cake,
I'm getting a bit peckish.
ケーキ食べたら小腹がすいてきたね
Now that you mention it,
it is long past lunchtime.
そういやとっくに昼過ぎてんじゃん
- Is lunch ready?
お昼まだ
Could you please stop living
so relentlessly fancy-free?
止めどなく自由に生きるの　やめてくれませんかね
ま　急に訪ねたのはこちらだしな
Now, we're the ones who dropped
in on you without warning,
so we'll put up the money.
元手は出そう
Why not order some of your
favorite sushi, or something?
お前の好きな寿司でも取ったらどうだ
No, that's okay.
いいですよ　鏡夜先輩におごってもらうなんて
Kyoya- senpai, I'm going to
dread it later if it's on you.
後がこわいから
Not to worry. This comes out of sales
of photos of you that we auctioned.
心配するな　オークションで捌いたお前の生写真の売上げだ
それって元手自分では
Then, isn't this really on me?
All right. I have a friend who
runs a nice sushi shop nearby,
わかりました　近くで知り合いのいいお寿司屋さんがありますから
so I'll give them a call.
They'll have some high-quality stuff.
電話してみます
あそこなら高級だし
"Even if the sushi pack
says 'premium' on it,
パックのお寿司は「特上」と書いてあっても高級とは言わないよ
you can't call it 'high-quality.'
Be very careful."
要注意
"Wastebasket"
知ってますよ　いくらなんでも
I know that much, at least.
"Fussing"
Aah, you dummy!
お父さんはお前に恥をかかせまいとせっかくさりげなさを装って
Daddy even took care to act all casual,
so as not to embarrass you!
I'd like to have something
made by you, Haru-chan.
僕　ハルちゃんの手料理が食べたいな
Honey-senpai!
ハニー先輩
なんて大胆発言を
What a daring thing to say!
We were holding back, ourselves!
俺達だって我慢してたのに
That's fine, but even starting now,
it will take some time.
いいですけど　今からじゃ時間かかりますよ
We'll wait!
待ってる
Maybe we should have asked her!
言ってよかったのか
We'll get to eat Haruhi's cooking!
ハルヒの手料理が食べられる
Well, I'll have to go to
the supermarket again.
それじゃまたスーパーに行かないと
Oh, I'm coming.
あ　行く
We want to come to the
commoners' supermarket, too.
僕らも行きたい　庶民スーパー
僕も僕も
Me, too! Me, too!
"It turns out everyone is going"
ま　いい経験かもな
Well, this might be a good experience.
Yay! Commoners' supermarket,
commoners' supermarket!
わい　庶民スーパー　庶民スーパー
楽しいね
Isn't this fun?
What's the use?
I guess I'm giving up my day off.
仕方ない　今日はもう休日返上で
先輩　行かないんですか
Senpai?
Aren't you coming?
Yeah, I'm coming.
行くけど　その前にお母様にご挨拶を
Before I do, though, I'm paying
my respects to your mother.
それは　わざわざすみません
Thanks for going to
the trouble of doing so.
Haruhi, you take after
your mother, huh?
ハルヒはお母さん似なんだな
はあ　父もそう言います
Yeah, my dad says so, too.
She was pretty. She looks smart, too.
綺麗な方だね　頭もよさそうだ
I don't know if she's pretty or not,
綺麗かわかんないけど　弁護士だったんです
but she was a lawyer.
Oh, I'll bet she was
a pretty capable one, too.
さぞかし有能だったんだろうな
You can't fool these eyes.
俺の目に狂いはないからな
先輩の目は知りませんけど
Senpai, I won't say anything
about your eyes...
...but...
Haruhi, Mom is going to do her
best today, so we're going to win!
ハルヒ　お母さん頑張ってくるから
今日も勝つ
...I do think she was.
そう思います
みんなを待たせてる　そろそろ行くか
W-we're keeping everyone waiting.
How about we get going?
イッテ
Yow...
I'm sorry, Haruhi!
ごめん　ハルヒ
いいえ　それより重い
It's okay, you're just heavy...
ただいま　ハルヒ
I'm home, Haruhi!
Why is the door open?
なんでドア開けっぱなし
Dad...
お父さん
突然帰宅した父
- All of a sudden, her father came home...
...from his shift at the tranny bar.
"Ranka, real name: Ryoji Fujioka (35)"
オカマバー勤務
- He saw his daughter pushed down...
...or so it appeared...
押し倒された
かのように見える
... on the floor,
娘
- being held down...
...or so it appeared...
押し倒している
かのように見える
... by an unfamiliar boy.
見知らぬ男
''Dad''? Does that mean this
tranny is Haruhi's father?
お父さんってことは
あのオカマさんはハルヒの父親ってことか
"Tamaki instantly understood
what the situation was."
Oh, Dad, welcome home.
あ　お父さん　お帰りなさい
Just stay calm.
This was just an accident.
落ち着け　俺　これは偶然の事故だ
If I explain what happened,
he'll understand.
ちゃんと説明すれば分かってもらえる
I'm sorry...
ごめんね　昨夜一人で留守番させちゃって
...for leaving you home
all alone last night.
You must have been lonesome.
寂しかったでしょう
That sounded really bad just now...
嫌だ
Oh, dear, my left arm aches,
like I just knocked down
なんか左手が今世紀最大の獣でも殴り倒したかのように痛いわ
the biggest beast of the century.
- Um... Father...
- Maybe I'm working too hard.
あのう　お父さん
仕事のしすぎかしら
熱いお茶でも飲みたいな
I'd sure like some hot tea.
Right!
はい　お茶
T-tea! Haruhi, do you boil
your water with firewood?
"All over the place!"
ハルヒ　お湯は薪で沸かすのか
薪はどこにくべたら
Where should I put the firewood?
嫌だ　なんかでかい害虫見つけちゃった
Oh, dear, I seem to have
found a huge pest.
大体先から何人の娘呼び捨てにしてんだこら
And exactly why have you
been dropping honorifics
when addressing my daughter!?
Sir, you were taking so long that we...
殿　なかなか来ないと思ったら
Oh, so that guy that passed us
downstairs is Haruhi's papa, after all.
あ　下ですれ違ったの　やっぱハルヒのパパさんだったんだ
光　馨　天の助け
Hikaru! Kaoru! It's divine intervention!
"Hikaru" "Kaoru"
あ　どうも
Ah, hello. We're Haruhi- san's good
friends, the Hitachiin Brothers.
僕らハルヒさんの親友の常陸院ブラザーズです
パパさんオカマさんですか
Papa- san, you're a tranny?
You're the first genuine
tranny we've ever seen.
本物のオカマさん初めて見ました
Sir, did you finally put
the moves on Haruhi?
殿　ついにハルヒに手でも出した
Sorry about that. This guy is
a dyed-in-the-wool ladies' man.
すみませんね　この人生粋な女好きで
弄んだ女は毛細血管の数より多いフェロモンマシンなもんで
He's a pheromone machine,
who's fooled around with more
girls than he's got capillaries.
弄んで
Fooled around?
違う　誰が遊びか
No! Who are you saying is
fooling around!? I sincerely...
俺は　俺は真剣に
Eh? Is he confessing his love?
告白？
真剣に娘さんのことを実の娘のように思っています
...sincerely think of your girl as
though she were my own daughter!
"Haruhi's father's first
impression of Tamaki"
"He's an idiot"
そうか　君たちが噂のホスト部ね
I see. You're the Host Club
I've been hearing about.
You really are a fine set of boys.
本当にいい男揃いね
どの子にしようか迷っちゃう
I don't know which one
of you I would take.
Huh, Haruhi?
ね　ハルヒ
Oh, you can just call me Ranka- san.
私のことは蘭花さんって呼んでくれていいわよ
"Ranka" is the professional name
I use at the tranny bar where I work.
蘭花って私が働いているオカマバーでの源氏名なの
源氏名って芸名みたいなもの
Professional name?
Like a stage name?
That's right, Mitsukuni- kun.
そうよう光邦君
あれ　なんで名前知ってるの
Huh? How do you know my name?
三年生の埴之塚君に銛之塚崇君
3rd-Years Haninozuka- kun
and Morinozuka Takashi- kun...
And you would be the 1st-Years,
in the same class as Haruhi,
それに１年生でハルヒと同じクラスの
Hitachiin Hikaru- kun
and Kaoru- kun, right?
常陸院光君　馨君でしょう
Which one of you is which, I wonder...
どっちがどっちかな
いつも話し聞いてるわよ
I'm always hearing stories about you.
Huh? Haruhi talks about us?
ハルヒが僕らの話を
Mm-mm, it's always from Kyoya- kun,
on the phone.
いつも鏡夜君からお電話で
Ranka- san, you really are beautiful.
本当蘭花さんはお美しいですね
What!?
なんと
Kyoya...
鏡夜
We're looking after
his precious daughter.
大切な娘さんをお預かりするんだ
ご挨拶はもちろん　定期的な報告は当然のことだろう
It's only natural that I'd say hello,
and give periodic reports on her, right?
本来ならお前の仕事のはずだが
Ordinarily, that should
be your job, right?
本当よくできた部長さんよね
You really are a fine club president.
あら　鏡夜君が副部長さんだったかしら
Oh, Kyoya- kun, you're
the vice-president, aren't you?
So the president isn't
good for much, huh?
よっぽとダメな方が部長さんなのね
Hold on there, Dad!
ちょっとお父さん
鏡夜先輩と繋がってるなんて聞いてませんよ
I never heard that you were
keeping contact with Kyoya- senpai!
ええ　だってハルヒってば学校の話全然してくんないんだもん
Huh? But Haruhi, you never tell
me about anything at school.
So then, without telling me, you...
だからって自分に内緒で
先輩も人んちの押し入れできのこ栽培するのやめてください
Senpai, would you please stop growing
mushrooms in other people's closets!?
Haruhi, the thing about you is...
ハルヒ　あんたって子は
怒った顔もかわいい
...you're even cute when you're angry!
なんつうか
There's something about this guy that
reminds me an awful lot of someone.
"Super-doting parent"
激しくだれかを彷彿とさせる人だな
殿の扱いがうまいわけだよハルヒは
It explains why Haruhi is so
good at handling his highness.
Oh, no, where are you going?
嫌だ　どこ行くの
The supermarket.
スーパーですよ
もう一人で買い出し行っちゃいます
I'm going shopping, all by myself.
I'll be right back, so everyone,
please behave yourselves.
すぐ戻るから皆さんはおとなしくしててください
Ah, Haruhi! We want to go to
the commoners' supermarket, too!
ハルヒ　俺らも庶民スーパー
That's okay, that's okay. Once she's
spoken, she won't listen to you.
いいのいいの
言い出したら聞かないんだから
"Mushroom Room"
That girl made up her
mind to go to Ouran,
あの子ったら　桜蘭に行く話も入学手続きも
and did all the enrollment
paperwork by herself.
全部自分で決めちゃってね
I'd like to respect her
spirit of independence,
自立精神は尊重したいけど
but sometimes, I wish
she'd depend on me more.
たまには甘えて欲しいわよね
"The Fujioka Family, 8 years ago"
Haruhi!
ハルヒ
"Fujioka Ryoji (Ranka)"
なんで今日参観日だって言わなかった
Why didn't you tell me that it
was Parents' Day at school today?
ダメ　お父さんは参観日に来ちゃダメ
Oh, no! Dad, you can't
come to Parents' Day!
"Matsubara Liquor Store -Sake"
Huh? Haruhi-chan is going
through a rebellious phase?
ハルヒちゃんが反抗期
I think you've got that wrong, don't you?
そりゃ違うんじゃねえかお前
She just couldn't invite
you to Parents' Day
オカマの父ちゃんが恥ずかしくて
because she's embarrassed
that daddy is a tranny, right?
参観日に呼べなかっただけだろう
Let me remind you,
I've always been bi!
言っとくけど　私は元々バイなの
But now that I've settled on
loving no one besides Kotoko,
けど　もう琴子以外は愛さないって決めたから
お店で働くのにウケがいいようにしてるだけ
I'm just trying to keep my reputation,
so I can keep working in the shop.
Hey, Haruhi-chan! Your dad's
gone and drunk himself stupid!
おいハルヒちゃん　お父さんが無茶な飲み方しやがってさ
Haruhi-chan, I'm home!
ハルちゃんただいま
Whoa, you reek of liquor.
お酒クサッ
参観日に行けなかったこと　相当ショックみたいでな
Looks like he was pretty upset
about not going to Parents' Day.
Invite him next time, okay?
次は呼んでやんなよ
No.
I'd rather let him have
some time off at home
参観日に来てくれるより　おうちでゆっくり休んでほしいもん
than come to Parents' Day.
He's exhausted, so he should stay
home and sleep on his day off.
疲れてるんだから
お休みの日はお家でずっと寝てていいし
I want him to take care of himself.
体のほうを大事にしてもらいたいもん
"Mushroom Room"
I'm grateful to you guys.
君たちには感謝してるのよ
She seems to be happy and enjoying
herself at school now, in her own way.
今学校でもそれなりに元気で楽しくやってるみたいだし
ね　須王環君
Right, Suou Tamaki- kun?
- Father-
- I knew who you were at first glance.
お父さん
一目でわかったわ
You're the idiot club president that
often comes up in Haruhi's stories.
ハルヒの話によく出てくるおバカな部長ってあんたのことだって
ホスト部のこと　ハルヒもちゃんと話してるのか
So Haruhi does talk about
the Host Club, does she?
Come to think of it, you're the one
そういえば君って　最後でハルヒを男と勘違いしていたんだってね
who mistook Haruhi for a boy
right up to the end, aren't you?
You just don't get it, do you?
You're awful.
わかってない子ね　最低
さて　そんなことよりみんな
Now then, let's never mind that,
why don't we all have
ourselves some fun?
いいことして遊ばない
I never knew.
知らなかった
Who'd have thought that
Dad and Kyoya- senpai
まさかお父さんが鏡夜先輩と連絡を取ってたなんて
were in touch with each other?
So we end up going
with her after all, huh?
結局一緒に行くんですね
これがいいことですか
This is what you meant by "fun"?
This is tailing-play, Kyoya- kun.
尾行プレイよ 鏡夜君
Those are good-looking boys, aren't they?
綺麗な男の子たちね
っていうか
タレントさんかしら
- Could they be TV personalities?
- Then again...
I just wanted to go walking around
with lots of fine boys in tow!
いい男をたくさん引き連れて歩いてみたかったのよ
Sure enough, this one and that
one are cut from the same cloth.
やはり　この人とあの人は同種だ
"Marutomi Supermarket"
Why do we need to go this far to
secretly watch how she's doing, Father?
どうしてわざわざこっそり様子を伺う必要があるのですか
お父様
あの子　母親を早くになくして
She lost her mother at an early age,
and took all of the housework,
家事はもちろん　買い物なんかも全部引き受けてくれたからさ
to say nothing of the shopping,
upon herself.
I couldn't help but develop
a habit of following after her.
ついつい後とかつけちゃう癖がついたの
父の愛っていうの
Would you call that a father's love?
Sure, I worry about her, you know?
やっぱり心配になるじゃない
I'm the only one who can
protect her, after all.
私しか守ってやれないんだから
"Haruhi, 6 years ago"
Huh?
あれ　お父さんどうしたの
Dad, what's the matter?
Oh, er, um... I just suddenly wanted
to carry your shopping basket, Haruhi!
えっと　急にハルヒの買い物カゴ持ちたいなあって
Dad loves to carry shopping baskets!
Can you believe it?
お父さん買い物カゴを持つの大好き
なんちゃって
You're weird.
変なの
Whether she doesn't know
how to rely on others,
甘え知らずっていうか　欲がないっていうか
or if she just has no desire to,
she doesn't give you
the chance to worry over her.
こっちが気遣う隙を与えないの
And yet, she has a way of saving
others without even realizing it.
そのくせ自分は無意識に人のこと救ってくれちゃったりすんのよね
Yeah, that's something...
それはわかります
...I understand.
There's no way you could understand it!
わかるわけないの
何よちょっと綺麗だからって
Where do you get off, just because
you're a little bit handsome?
言っとくけど　私はまだまだあの子を手放す気はないんだから
I'm warning you, I'm not
ready to let go just yet!
Please, let go...
手を離してください
You've got some nerve, for someone
who's only known her a few days!
昨日今日の付き合いのくせに生意気だ
ってなわけで　あんたは敵　敵とみなす
And so...
You're the enemy!
I consider you an enemy!
"Ranka"
Huh? Tamaki- senpai, what's the matter?
あれ　環先輩どうしたんですか
Oh, er, um... I just suddenly wanted
to carry your shopping basket, Haruhi!
えっと　急にハルヒの買い物カゴ持ちたいなあって
Yes, Daddy loves to carry shopping
baskets! Can you believe it?
そう　お父さん買い物カゴを持つの大好き
なんちゃって
You're weird.
変なの
Oh, mushrooms...
あ　きのこ
So, "time service" means
there's a time limit, huh?
タイムサービスとは時間制限があるのか
Ah, there's a whole stack
of commoners' coffee.
庶民コーヒーが山積みになってる
何か食べたいものありますか
- Was there anything you wanted to eat?
- Just like at the international
market, huh?
えっと　お鍋
Um, a stewpot. With lots of meat
in it, and no chrysanthemum.
お肉がいっぱいで春菊が入ってないの
You're right.
そうですね
When there are a lot of people,
a stewpot would be better, huh?
人数が多いときは鍋物がいいですね
It's kind of warm for it, though.
暑いけど
Even so, if at some point,
それでもいつか
the day comes when that
unselfish girl dearly wants
欲のないあの子が
ただ一人の人のそばにいることを　心から望む日が来るのなら
to have just one person at her side...
Sure enough, it galls me
just thinking about it!
やっぱ考えただけでムカつくわ
はい春菊
- Here, have some chrysanthemum...
and some more chrysanthemum...
- I wanted meat...
肉
はい春菊
- Wow, there's so much meat!
- This is delicious.
- What's going on here?
食え春菊
おいしいよ
何だろうね
殿　そんな小さな妹なんていたの
Sir, do you really have such
a little younger sister?
いいんだ　今日から俺がお兄ちゃまだよ
That's okay, as of today,
I will be your big brother!
そんな無責任な発言はやめくれませんか
Would you stop making such
irresponsible declarations?
Next time, "Big Brother is a Prince"
桜蘭高校ホストクラブ　来週も
Ouran High School Host Club will
be waiting for you, next week!
お待ちしております